Manos Pavlidakis

• Email • LinkedIn • Github • Scholar • +30 6974121338 • Greece, Crete

I am a software engineer with a Ph.D. (defense scheduled on 9th January 2024) in Computer Science and Engineering from the University of Crete, Greece. My doctoral research on the "*Transparent Spatial Sharing of Multiple and Heterogeneous Accelerators*" provided extensive hands-on experience in various accelerator programming models and runtimes, including OpenCL, CUDA, and ROCm. Additionally, I am well-versed in popular machine learning frameworks such as PyTorch, Caffe, and TensorFlow, showcasing a comprehensive skill set at the forefront of technology. I have cultivated a profound familiarity with CUDA and NVIDIA GPUs due to my attendance at more than four courses and my research. A testament to my proficiency and commitment to the field is my role in identifying and reporting two core performance issues related to NVIDIA GPU sharing (ID3559606, ID3350973).

TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES

C/C++, CUDA, OpenCL, ROCm, CUDA PTX virtual assembly, Java

Git, Containers, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Caffe, Bash scripting

NVIDIA GPUs, AMD GPUs, Intel Altera FPGA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant at CARV, ICS-FORTH	Sep. 2017 – Jan. 2024
• Design and develop <i>Arax</i> , a runtime that manages and shares transparently multiple and heterogeneous accelerators	
Research Engineer at CARV, ICS-FORTH	Jan. 2017 – Sep. 2017
 Design and develop Vinetalk, a framework that simplifies FPGA access while enabling FPGA sharing across different applications 	
Intern at CARV, ICS-FORTH	Jun. 2016 – Sep. 2016
Working on implementing an HDFS library over NoSQL DB	
Free launcher	Jun. 2013 – Jul. 2014
Android application and website development	

EDUCATION and CERTIFICATIONS

Ph.D. at Computer Science Department, University of Crete	Sep. 2017 – Jan. 2024
MSc at High Performance Distributed Computing track, Vrije Universiteit (VU) Amsterdam	Sep. 2014 – Jun. 2016
BSc (integrated master) at the Department of Information and Communication Systems Engineering, University of Aegean, Samos	Sep. 2006 – Jun. 2012
NVIDIA certification: Fundamentals of Accelerated Computing with CUDA C/C++	Aug. 2022
NVIDIA certification: Scaling CUDA C++ Applications to Multiple Nodes	May 2022

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant	
Digital design (CS120)	Winters 2017 – 2022
Programming lab (CS255)	Springs 2017 - 2019
Embedded System Lab (CS428)	

• Theory of Computation (CS280) Springs 2020 Winter 2	
PUBLICATIONS	2023
Guardian: Data Isolation for Multi-Tenant GPU Sharing (Under Submission)	
Arax: A Runtime Framework for Decoupling Applications from Heterogeneous Accelerators (SoCC'22)	2022
TReM: A Task Revocation Mechanism for GPUs. (HPCC'20)	2020
The VINEYARD integrated framework for hardware accelerators in the cloud. (SAMOS'18)	
VineTalk: Simplifying Software Access and Sharing of FPGAs in Datacenters. (FPL'17)	
KVFS: An HDFS library over NoSQL DB. (CLOSER '16)	2016
Introducing Touchstroke: Keystroke-based Authentication System for Smartphones. (Journal: Security and Communication Networks)	2016
FELLOWSHIPS and AWARDS	
cholarship from ADMHE for the academic year 2020-2021	
Scholarship from ADMHE for the academic year 2019-2020	2020
\$1,000 in Google Cloud Platform from Google for Education	202
Two Intel Altera FPGAs (Arria 10) from the Intel FPGA Academic Program	201
One NVIDIA Titan V from the NVIDIA GPU Grant Program	201
CONFERENCES, WORKSHOPS, and other EVENTS	
Participate at NVIDIA event hosted at SC23	2023
Participate in the event "NVIDIA AI and Data Science Virtual Summit"	
Participate in the event organized by EuroCC, "NVIDIA Developer Day for EuroCC"	
Participate in the workshop "Seamlessly Migrate CUDA Code to SYCL Code with SYCLomatic"	
Participate in the event "Facebook Systems @Scale Summer"	
Participate in the event "Advanced SYCL Concepts – Graphs and Dependencies"	
Present "Arax" (and participate) at the 13th Symposium on Cloud Computing (SoCC'22)	2022
Present at EuroCC EU event: 1st presentation: Why Accelerators? GPUs and their advantages. 2nd presentation: Introduction to CUDA	
Reviewer at ACM Transactions on Architecture and Coder Optimization (TACO'22)	
Head of the Organizing Committee for the 3rd Career Fair: Meet the companies	
Present "TReM" at Microsoft Research, Cambridge, Virtual Workshop on Next-Generation Cloud Infrastructure	202
Head of the Organizing Committee for the event Career Fair: Prepare for the Interview	
Head of the Organizing Committee for the 2nd Career Fair: Meet the Companies	
Present "TReM" (and participate) at the International Conference on High-Performance Computing and Communications (HPCC'20)	202
Participate and host virtual sessions at the European Conference on Computer Systems (EuroSys'20)	
Participate in the conference Symposium on Operating Systems Design & Implementation (OSDI'20)	
Participate in the conference USENIX 2020 Annual Technical Conference (ATC'20)	
Participate in Intel's webinar 2020, "Migrate Existing CUDA Applications to DPC++ Code"	
Participate in the International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium (IPDPS'20)	
Participate in the conference International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA'20)	
Head of the Organizing Committee for the 1 st GSA-CSD'19: Graduate Student Conference	201
Present "Flexy; Elastic Provisioning of Accelerators in Single Node with Multi-GPUs" (and participate) at the HIPEAC Summer School ACACES'18	